Alice Zhang

User Experience Designer with 7 years of experience in SaaS for B2B environments specializing in visual design, accessibility, and UX strategy. Focusing on transforming ambiguity into clear, user-centred solutions, with a focus on creating memorable experiences.

EXPERIENCE

UI and UX Designer - Pelesys for CAE

Richmond, Canada | January 2022 - September 2024

- Designed Figma and Sketch mockups for the Learning Management System app redesign, collaborating with an internationally-based cross-functional team of developers, QA, and product managers.
- Improved existing design of the fill-in-the-blanks question type, enhancing the exam creation process for course admins.
- Collaborated with CAE design team to develop a new in-house design system used across all redesign projects.

UX Designer - Evident Point Software for PressReader

Richmond, Canada | January 2019 - November 2021

- Established project foundation for a 500K online school workbook initiative at PressReader's EdTech department; project green-lit after stakeholder presentation.
- Led competitive analysis of 14 products in user research, identifying improvement areas and presenting findings to inform product design.
- Updated client visual branding and print design, adjusting brand colors to meet WCAG AA contrast standards.

UX Designer & Developer - Plaid Consulting

Vancouver, Canada | May 2018 - July 2019

- Created an interactive web app prototype in Adobe XD and Proto.io, incorporating brand colours and typography.
- Initiated front-end development of responsive webpages using ReactJS, Bootstrap, SASS, NodeJS, and tracked with Git Bash.
- Conducted user research through user interviews with data analysts and institutional researchers to define user needs for the web app.

Web Communications Assistant - DFO Canada

Vancouver, Canada | September 2015 - April 2016

- Updated DFO government webpages to use a responsive, accessible HTML/CSS and Bootstrap template.
- Designed fitness centre newsletters in Photoshop and Illustrator.

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, Canada

BSc in Interactive Arts and Technology | 2020 Certificate in Computing Studies | 2020

Malmö University, Sweden

Interaction Design BA Course in Full-time Exchange Program | 2017

- alice-zhang-portfolio.com
- alzh13579@gmail.com
- **L** +1 778 788 3568
- in linkedin.com/in/alice-zhang
- alice_slicez
- alice_slicez

DESIGN SKILLS

Product Design
User Interface Design
Visual Design
Wireframing
Print Design

UX METHODS

UX Research
User Interviewing
Competitor Product Analysis
User Journey Mapping
Persona Creation
Usability Testing
UX Writing
Accessibility Testing
AI Prompt Engineering

TOOLS

Figma Sketch Adobe Creative Suite Miro, LucidChart Notion Airtable

CODING

HTML CSS/SASS Javascript Git Bash

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCIES

English Mandarin Chinese